Great job finishing this section on Project environments I told you it was a lot of information right.
A lot of things to cover.
Well you did it knocked out Section 8 here on Project environments.
Good job in this section we talked about Enterprise environmental factors and organizational process
assets which you know as ETF and OPM.
So we'll see that over and over throughout this course.
We'll look at the different processes policies and procedures that are unique to your environment that
you have to follow as a PM where you work.
And we looked at organizational knowledge repositories the new process and Pinback six that we'll see
coming up about knowledge management.
So you can see how that's going to tie in.
So this sets us up for this idea of knowledge repositories that how do we take that data that information
from our past projects and how can we quickly access that and be able to apply it and use it in our
current project.
So we're talking about cataloguing.
So how do you catalog it electronically.
How do you archive it.
Is it retrievable.
So we have to go dig through you know a closet somewhere.
Hopefully not.
But it's electronic that you can search it and retrieve it.
Organizational process assets these are part of your knowledge repository repositories so historical
information.
So that allows me then to pull from that and apply it to my current project.
We always archive that closure.
So it's never an option to not archive.
We always archive a closure because that's part of the business value.
That's part of the things that we're creating as part of the project Project deliverables are not always
things that the customer gets.
It could also be things that we get and that we retain as the organization.
So knowledge gain tools equipment.
In this case it's knowledge.
So how do we retrieve that knowledge.
We looked at organizational systems and framework.
How your company structured and the systems that you follow to get work done or that you create to get
work done.
You need a system.
And we looked at those different structure types probably the most important thing in the section are
the organizational structure types.
I know you completed an assignment right on recognizing these different organizational types really
important.
Good job.
And then we talked about the project management office.
OK very good.
You've covered a lot of material you've knocked out this stuff on project environment.
Keep moving forward.
We're getting closer and closer to getting into those knowledge areas where I know you want to go.
But this that's really important as well you're going to be tested on this and this will affect how
you answer questions successfully.
All right.
I'm proud of you.
You've made great progress.
Keep going.
You can do it.